<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Random Coding</title><link>http://dlitvakb.github.io/</link><description>A personal coding blog, where I will share some code and some thoughts and experiences</description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 14:11:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Teaching Agile with Minecraft</title><link>http://dlitvakb.github.io/posts/teaching-agile-with-minecraft.html</link><dc:creator>David Litvak Bruno</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I got involved for the first time in the Agile community in Argentina,
very rapidly, the feeling of willing to transfer this concepts to everybody
started emerging in me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, I started being an assistant teacher at a class called
"Methodologies for Team Conduction" in my university, in which my job, aside from
grading tests and practices, was to teach my experiences working in Systems Engineering
and to create an Agile Methodologies assignment in which students could get a grasp on
what being Agile meant for a team, and how could this impact in their day to day
work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson has been doing really well with how we were teaching it, until this semester,
when we found that one of the two courses we teach was lacking engagement (not just for
the Agile class, it was like that all the time), which really got me into thinking on
how could we improve our way of teaching in order to make it the most engaging possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enter Minecraft&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it's release, I've been an elusive player, but a faithful follower of the game and
some of it's most reknowned players. And for all this time, I've noticed that there is a
lot of people using the game in so many ways other than it's original
"build a house, survive the night" marketing, that it really intrigued me on how I could
benefit from knowing all this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was totally blank until last week, when I saw a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-aiBSNumx0A"&gt;documentary&lt;/a&gt;
about Game Story Development, in which it's second part it talks about kids using Minecraft
in their schools, and that as a result they were getting team-quality approaches to solving
problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after a few days of work, I got a prototype map in which 8 teams can work on a blank slate
of land, in which we define some goals and we have Scrum-like iterations for the students
to make their planning, development and retrospectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night, I invited the rest of the teachers to help me playtest this concept. And the
results were more than great! It was really, really fun to do this activity. It also helped
me understand what to improve in order to allow for better interaction with the students,
and also taught me that the entry barrier is near to none, as one of the teachers had never
played Minecraft before, and was completely into the activity after the first 5 minutes of
the playtest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still need to finish the map, and have it completely polished before we release it into
the university. But our first test was more than successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we need to try it out in the University, see how the students take it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this is a great success!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:wq&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>agile</category><category>gamification</category><category>minecraft</category><guid>http://dlitvakb.github.io/posts/teaching-agile-with-minecraft.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 14:59:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Get involved with your community</title><link>http://dlitvakb.github.io/posts/get-involved-with-your-community.html</link><dc:creator>David Litvak Bruno</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Development as a whole is a people job, most of your work involves
getting in touch with other people, by getting their opinion, solving
some of their needs or reaching out for help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, most of us, love our craft, our tools, our languages. This creates
the innate need for people to share their interests, hobbies and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, communities were created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Joining a Community&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step of getting involved is joining a community. To do this,
there are plentyful of ways. Most communities have gatherings, conferences,
mailing lists, forums or IRC chats. You can participate by joining to either one or
multiple of this communication channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just by joining the community, you already get benefits, you get to know
what the community is talking about, what are the main interests, who are
the most relevant members and the most interesting projects.
This already gives you a great hint in what you can contribute back to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to contribute&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are multiple ways for contributing to a community, each has their own,
be sure to research them. But most notably, the majority of the communities
have a list of ongoing projects, job-lists and gatherings in which you can
collaborate and contribute to. Also, you can propose your own projects if they
fit the culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another great way of contributing is helping people with their doubts. Helping
to solve another persons problem is really benefitial when done in a public
environment, as it stands for a great documentation source in case something similar
happens to raise up again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Benefits from contributing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great part from contributing is that, in some way or form, you're always getting
something in return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you'll get back from contributing is the joy of helping out other people
(and many times yourself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another great benefit is that you will be participating in whatever is hyped by the
community, which will polish your skills in that matter to the maximum possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By helping out members, you're most likely getting exposure, your name will start
popping up more and more frequently when in need to do something. This is really great,
because it gives you a lot of opportunities to keep contributing and also the possibility
to get known outside of your community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As our job is mostly interacting with people, try as much as you can to get involved in
every community that you're interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The joy of helping others and getting to know and learn what's trendy is one of the best
return on investments you can put on your time and effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my advice is, start reaching out to your community, you'll get a kick out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:wq&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>community</category><guid>http://dlitvakb.github.io/posts/get-involved-with-your-community.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 22:57:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why am I coding?</title><link>http://dlitvakb.github.io/posts/why-am-i-coding.html</link><dc:creator>David Litvak Bruno</dc:creator><description>&lt;h3&gt;The Beginning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is David Litvak Bruno, from Argentina, a simple guy
that found huge interest in coding at the early age of 4, when we
bought our first computer with my dad, a Packard-Bell 386.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was back in 1994, when I was telling my mom I wanted to be
an "Ingeniero en puputación" ("poputer engineer" in Baby-Spanish).
My interest started when watching my first lines of DOS hacking,
just installing a bunch of random stuff on that computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many years passed between that and my first actual line of code.
It was in 2004, when I was in the second year of my Highschool education.
My Technology course teacher started teaching us the basics of Visual Basic.
At that time, I thought Visual Basic was THE BOMB, and everything around me
could be modeled just by using a couple of &lt;code&gt;If&lt;/code&gt; statements in
Visual Basic. Oh my, those were great times, I had so much fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some years later, when I entered College, I met &lt;a href="http://codescience.wordpress.com/"&gt;Juan Manuel Garcia&lt;/a&gt;,
who is now one of my best friends. He introduced me to Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was what, if I already was in love with programming, definitely
made me dive like a crazy man into code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started doing all kinds of tutorials, I was so interested in it's syntax,
it's simplicity, it's everything. This got me introduced to &lt;a href="http://python.org.ar/"&gt;PyAr&lt;/a&gt;,
the Python Argentina Community, which was helding a series of talks
in a venue nearby my place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stupid simple apps started flowing like crazy. Soon I started getting into bigger
and bigger projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, in 2011, after some jobs doing C# and VB.Net, I got my first job using Python,
this was an incredible journey. It got me learning a lot of libraries I'd never heard about,
it got me motivated to start writing my own libraries and reaching out to more
and more developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2012, I got my first opportunity to give something back to the community,
I had a spot in PyDay Lujan and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L_wm5cENFJQ"&gt;PyCon 2012&lt;/a&gt;,
where I was able to show some of the stuff that was amazing me the most at that time (and still do amaze me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Today&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I'm looking forward to what's my next project. I'm working on ideas to continue
giving back to the community that took me in so kindly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:wq&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog</category><category>code</category><category>programming</category><category>reasons</category><guid>http://dlitvakb.github.io/posts/why-am-i-coding.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 19:54:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>