<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Random Coding (agile)</title><link>http://dlitvakb.github.io/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 14:11:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Teaching Agile with Minecraft</title><link>http://dlitvakb.github.io/posts/teaching-agile-with-minecraft.html</link><dc:creator>David Litvak Bruno</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I got involved for the first time in the Agile community in Argentina,
very rapidly, the feeling of willing to transfer this concepts to everybody
started emerging in me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, I started being an assistant teacher at a class called
"Methodologies for Team Conduction" in my university, in which my job, aside from
grading tests and practices, was to teach my experiences working in Systems Engineering
and to create an Agile Methodologies assignment in which students could get a grasp on
what being Agile meant for a team, and how could this impact in their day to day
work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson has been doing really well with how we were teaching it, until this semester,
when we found that one of the two courses we teach was lacking engagement (not just for
the Agile class, it was like that all the time), which really got me into thinking on
how could we improve our way of teaching in order to make it the most engaging possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enter Minecraft&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it's release, I've been an elusive player, but a faithful follower of the game and
some of it's most reknowned players. And for all this time, I've noticed that there is a
lot of people using the game in so many ways other than it's original
"build a house, survive the night" marketing, that it really intrigued me on how I could
benefit from knowing all this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was totally blank until last week, when I saw a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-aiBSNumx0A"&gt;documentary&lt;/a&gt;
about Game Story Development, in which it's second part it talks about kids using Minecraft
in their schools, and that as a result they were getting team-quality approaches to solving
problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after a few days of work, I got a prototype map in which 8 teams can work on a blank slate
of land, in which we define some goals and we have Scrum-like iterations for the students
to make their planning, development and retrospectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night, I invited the rest of the teachers to help me playtest this concept. And the
results were more than great! It was really, really fun to do this activity. It also helped
me understand what to improve in order to allow for better interaction with the students,
and also taught me that the entry barrier is near to none, as one of the teachers had never
played Minecraft before, and was completely into the activity after the first 5 minutes of
the playtest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still need to finish the map, and have it completely polished before we release it into
the university. But our first test was more than successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we need to try it out in the University, see how the students take it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this is a great success!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:wq&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>agile</category><category>gamification</category><category>minecraft</category><guid>http://dlitvakb.github.io/posts/teaching-agile-with-minecraft.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 14:59:50 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>