<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Random Coding (reasons)</title><link>http://dlitvakb.github.io/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 14:11:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Why am I coding?</title><link>http://dlitvakb.github.io/posts/why-am-i-coding.html</link><dc:creator>David Litvak Bruno</dc:creator><description>&lt;h3&gt;The Beginning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is David Litvak Bruno, from Argentina, a simple guy
that found huge interest in coding at the early age of 4, when we
bought our first computer with my dad, a Packard-Bell 386.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was back in 1994, when I was telling my mom I wanted to be
an "Ingeniero en puputación" ("poputer engineer" in Baby-Spanish).
My interest started when watching my first lines of DOS hacking,
just installing a bunch of random stuff on that computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many years passed between that and my first actual line of code.
It was in 2004, when I was in the second year of my Highschool education.
My Technology course teacher started teaching us the basics of Visual Basic.
At that time, I thought Visual Basic was THE BOMB, and everything around me
could be modeled just by using a couple of &lt;code&gt;If&lt;/code&gt; statements in
Visual Basic. Oh my, those were great times, I had so much fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some years later, when I entered College, I met &lt;a href="http://codescience.wordpress.com/"&gt;Juan Manuel Garcia&lt;/a&gt;,
who is now one of my best friends. He introduced me to Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was what, if I already was in love with programming, definitely
made me dive like a crazy man into code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started doing all kinds of tutorials, I was so interested in it's syntax,
it's simplicity, it's everything. This got me introduced to &lt;a href="http://python.org.ar/"&gt;PyAr&lt;/a&gt;,
the Python Argentina Community, which was helding a series of talks
in a venue nearby my place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stupid simple apps started flowing like crazy. Soon I started getting into bigger
and bigger projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, in 2011, after some jobs doing C# and VB.Net, I got my first job using Python,
this was an incredible journey. It got me learning a lot of libraries I'd never heard about,
it got me motivated to start writing my own libraries and reaching out to more
and more developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2012, I got my first opportunity to give something back to the community,
I had a spot in PyDay Lujan and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L_wm5cENFJQ"&gt;PyCon 2012&lt;/a&gt;,
where I was able to show some of the stuff that was amazing me the most at that time (and still do amaze me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Today&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I'm looking forward to what's my next project. I'm working on ideas to continue
giving back to the community that took me in so kindly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:wq&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog</category><category>code</category><category>programming</category><category>reasons</category><guid>http://dlitvakb.github.io/posts/why-am-i-coding.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 19:54:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>